October 8th, 2017

Canadian Multi-Stakeholder Forum Selection Committee

Dear Colleagues/Collègues,

I am very excited about the formation of the Multi-stakeholder Forum and humbly submit my application to become a member to represent civil society in the ongoing dialogue about Canada's Third Biennial Plan to the Open Government Partnership (OGP). Open government is a personal passion of mine and core to rebooting and revitalizing modern democracy.

As an open data advocate, open data is not an end in itself. Open data is a foundation for open government to proceed; without open data and information, citizen engagement is not a balanced playing field and true collaboration between government and civil society is, at best, stifled and at its worst, ingenuine and patronizing. Canada's participation in the OGP is a major move toward institutionalizing open government in Canada and civil society must do its part to work with the Canadian government to make this commitment a success. I would be honoured to be a voice in this process.

As a New Brunswick native, I understand the Maritime perspective on the Canadian government. With over 15 years in Ontario and 6 years in Ottawa, I also have a solid understanding of the Ontario civil society experience and the forces and constraints experienced by those working in the federal government. During 2017 I have been on the Ontario Advisory Groups for the International Open Data Charter and Public Service Open Government Training.

I had the opportunity to attend the OGP Summit in Paris as one of Ontario's civil society representative. At the summit I had the honour of attending a breakfast hosted by Federal Minister Scott Brison and Ontario Minister Liz Sandals and had the opportunity to lead a discussion about the need for better open government coordination and collaboration. I also co-hosted a International Open Data Day event with the Treasury Board Secretariat of Canada. This past summer I represented Ontario civil society at the Subnational workshop in Washington D.C.

As the founder of the Open Data Institute node in Ottawa and an active participant in the last three Canadian Open Data Summits, I am well connected to the national open data movement. I am also a co-organizer of the Ottawa Civic Tech group and have had the opportunity to be involved in the emergence of a national civic tech community. These communities offer unique perspectives into the current Canadian civil society zeitgeist that I can leverage to broaden the voice of the forum.

| Regardless of the outcome of this process, I will continue to provide a strong civil society voice |  |  |  |
|--|--|--|--|
| for a collaborative and sustainable Canadian open government.                                      |  |  |  |
|  |  |  |  |
| Sincerely,   |  |  |  |

Open Data Institute Veracify

Rob Davidson

# ROBERT DAVIDSON

A results oriented technology leader possessing a unique combination of business acumen with technology vision. Highly effective in bringing structure and collaborative process to rapidly changing environments.

# **BUSINESS SKILLS**

- Ability to assess business situations quickly, glean pertinent decision criteria and formulate appropriate strategic responses.
- Proven success at building, developing and leading highly effective agile teams which were determined to exceed all team and organizational goals set for them.
- Uncommon ability to rapidly learn and adapt to new industries and business issues as demonstrated through effectiveness in providing world-class business solutions to government, retail, financial, telecommunication, advertising, publishing, manufacturing and technology industries.
- Superior communication and presentation skills enhanced by the ability to distill complex concepts into messages easily understood by CEOs and frontline workers alike

### **EDUCATION**

- 1991 **Master of Business Administration** The University of Western Ontario. Nelson M. Davis Scholarship.
- 1988 **Bachelor of Science (Data Analysis)** The University of New Brunswick. Lieutenant-Governor of New Brunswick Silver Medal, C. Cusack Award, Dean's List, R.L.W. Memorial Prize, Computer Centre Prize, University Faculty Scholarship.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Veracify, Ottawa, Ontario Principal Consultant, Owner 2016 - Present

Data consultancy focused on data strategy, storytelling and visualization. Projects include:

- Innovative AI product for measuring and managing employee engagement.
- Social media analysis of Canadian Federal Election.

Freelancer 2009 - 2016

During this period my primary function was caring for my children and raising them to be strong, independent individuals. As part of my ongoing career development and interest in technology I devoted time to researching my professional interests including open source analytic tools, machine learning, social media analysis and mobile app development.

# Kinek, Saint John, New Brunswick

2005 - 2009

# Director, Marketing

- Led all aspects of Marketing including: Product Management, Product Marketing, Competitive Intelligence, Marketing Communications, Marketing Strategy.
- Infused needed experience into immature start-up.

# University of New Brunswick, Saint John

2004 - 2005

# Co-Director, MBA Program & Lecturer

- Responsible for the day-to-day administration of the MBA program.
- Co-lead the redesign of the MBA program for launch in 2006-2007.
- Lectured in the undergraduate courses in the Faculty of Business on e-commerce and business strategy.

# **Independent Research**

2002 - 2004

During this period I began to study and research emerging technologies and fostered my continuing fascination for the power of data. Also primary caregiver to young family, managing transition from living in the U.S. to returning to Canada.

# **Openpages,** Westford, MA.

2002 - 2002

# Director, Sales Engineering

• Led, developed and managed presales team.

### Notara, New York, NY.

2001 - 2002

### Chief Technologist

### Vice President, Business Development & Product Development

- Developed product and technology roadmap for the next generation of products.
- Co-lead with President on merger and acquisition activity.

# InterWorld, New York, NY.

1996 - 2001

# Vice President, E-Commerce Technology & Vice President, Strategy, Alliances

- Managed a team of senior technologists.
- Member of executive management team; helping define corporate, alliance and product strategies.
- Led technology interactions with customers, alliance partners, industry analysts, financial analysts and international press.
- Led solution and technology due diligence for all funding and merger and acquisition activity.

### Director, World-Wide Sales Engineering

- Responsible for hiring, developing and managing global Sales Engineering team.
- Lead initiative to build and jumpstart European Sales Team.
- Helped re-build Western U.S. Sales Team.

# Open Market Inc., Cambridge, MA.

1995 - 1996

# Sales Engineer

- Responsible for e-commerce solutions and technology positioning for Canadian sales.
- E-commerce evangelist for field operations, supporting sales activities across North America

# **Platinum Software**, Mississauga, Ontario.

1994 - 1995

# **Consulting Manager**

- Lead financial system implementation projects engagements.
- Canadian representative on International Design Review Group.
- Spearheaded business re-engineering practice for Canadian consulting operation.

# **D&B Software**, Toronto, Ontario.

1991 - 1994

### Senior Consultant

- Provided consulting services and project leadership for financial systems implementation engagements.
- Project Manager on a \$1 million engagement at a major telecommunications company.

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Instrumental in growing InterWorld from a small startup to a publicly traded company valued, at peak, at over 2 billion dollars.
- InterWorld's Global Sales MVP 1997, 1998 and 1999.
- Co-lead the successful 2002 sale of Notara to venture capital firm.
- Co-lead the redesign of the UNBSJ MBA program in 2004-2005.

# MEMBERSHIPS & RECENT SPEAKING ENGAGEMENTS

Open Data Institute, Ottawa node Founder

2016 - Present

# Ontario Treasury Board Secretariat OGP Advisory Group

| • | International Open Data Charter         | 2017 - Present |
|---|---|----------------|
| • | <b>Open Government Training Program</b> | 2017 - Present |

# Meetups

| Civic Tech Ottawa (co-organizer)          | 2016 - Present |
|---|----------------|
| Data for Good Ottawa                      | 2015 - Present |
| Open Data Ottawa Book Club (co-organizer) | 2014 - Present |

# **Recent Speaking Engagements**

# Canadian Open Data Summit 2016 (Saint John, NB) 2016

- "Social Impact of Open Data" panelist
- Presented Lightning Talk on "The Rise of the Citizen Data Scientist"

# Open Data in Action (Seoul, Korea)

2016

• Presented "Expanding Open Data Horizons with R and RStudio"

# Conference Board of Canada 2017 (Montreal, QC) 2017

• Council of Public Affairs Executives on "On the Data Horizon"

# International Open Data Day 2017 (Ottawa, ON) 2017

• Co-hosted Ottawa event with Treasury Board of Canada Secretariat

# Conference Board of Canada 2017 (Montreal, QC) 2017

• Strategic Human Resources Management Council and Public Sector Executive Network on "Open Data and Collaboration"

# GO Open Data Conference 2017 (London, ON) 2017

- "Canada's Growing Civic Tech Movement" panelist
- Presented on "Bridging the Canadian Divide"

# Canadian Open Data Summit 2017 (Edmonton, AB) 2017

- "Nonprofits + Open Data = New Perspectives" panelist
- Presented Lightning Talk on "Open Data versus Post-Truth Politics"